[Gon] He’s so far beyond me.
But he’s not so far out of reach
I can’t catch up someday.
I need more training in Nen.
I’ve gotta find a power
that’s as strong as Hisoka’s!
[theme song playing]
[birds squawking]
[Gon] Aunt Mito!
Aunt Mito!
Aunt Mito, hey!
Gon.
Gon!
Aunt Mito!
[Gon laughs]
I’m finally home!
Welcome back.
And you must be Killua.
What?
GING X AND X GON
[Mito] My goodness,
I wish you’d let me know
you were coming home.
I didn’t have time to prepare!
It’s fine. No big deal.
Maybe not to you!
But your friend just came all this way…
[Killua] Oh, don’t worry about me!
[Mito]
Honestly, you should’ve called at least!
I’ve been worried sick!
[Mito] Are you listening?
[muffled laughter]
[Mito] Oh, right.
You two go and take your baths
while I finish supper.
And put out all of your dirty clothes.
I’ll do laundry.
-[Gon] Okay, later.
-Right now!
You’ve got ten seconds!
-One. Two. Three.
-[Gon] Ooh!
-Is she always like this?
-[Mito] Four.
-Five.
-Pretty much.
-[Mito] Six. Seven.
-Come on. Hurry up!
[Mito] Eight. Nine. Ten.
Yeah… Now this is what I call living!
[Mito] Okay, let's eat.
[Killua] Wow! It looks delicious!
What’s going on?
We’re offering our gratitude.
-‘Kay, what does that mean?
-Well? Let’s dig in!
Please, help yourself
to whatever you like!
[Killua] Thanks!
-[Gon] Oh yeah… Aunt Mito.
-Hmm?
Look!
This is a Hunter License.
Wow…
It looks pretty ordinary.
There.
[Gon yelps]
Come on! What do you think you’re doing?!
[Mito laughs] I’m kidding!
You know I wouldn’t do that.
[Gon] Well… I just hope it still works.
Aunt Mito!
I’m gonna go show Killua
around the island! ‘Kay?
But won’t that take a while?
Want me to pack lunch?
[Gon] It’s okay!
We’ll find something to eat in the forest!
[Gon] Whoa!
[both laughing]
-[Killua straining]
-[both laughing]
Where are they? It’s getting late.
It’s been a little while
since he was last home.
And it’s the first time
he brought a friend with him.
They’ll be back pretty late.
I’m sure they’re fine.
Yes, you’re probably right.
Maybe I should take some food out to them.
[crickets chirping]
-[Killua] Hey, Gon…
-Hm?
So, uh… What are you gonna do now?
[Gon] Well, I think I’m gonna rest up here
for a little bit
while I gather all the information
that I’m gonna need.
For when I finally go to Yorknew City
to find my dad.
[Killua] Oh.
I gotcha.
What do you think I should do?
You should stay here, too!
Then go to Yorknew City with me!
I know. I am coming with you.
But that isn’t what I meant.
I was just thinking I admire you.
There’s nothing I wanna do.
You’ve got your thing.
I don’t have anything.
There are plenty of things
I don’t wanna do, though.
Like stay in that house,
or take over the family business.
I guess I’m a little bit... jealous.
-[Gon] Killua.
-Huh?
It’s fun.
Hanging out with you, I mean.
Hey… Where did that come from?
Whale Island’s an outpost.
It’s where fishermen stay
when they’re at sea a long time.
Not a lot of people who live here
are natives.
There is a girl around my age
but I just never got to know her
very well.
So, you’re kinda my first friend.
My same age and everything!
Yeah, I know what you mean.
Being stuck in that house all day…
and spending all my time
learning how to kill people.
You were my first real friend.
When we’re together, you have fun, right?
Huh?
I guess so, yeah.
I do too, so I think
we should stick together!
Let’s travel around
and see the whole world!
Just you and me!
You don’t know how embarrassing
you’re being right now, huh?
[Gon chuckles sheepishly]
I’ll go look for my dad…
and you can look for something
you really want to do.
It’s gonna be so fun!
You’re right.
Doesn’t sound half bad.
Fine! I’ll look for something to do…
but in the meantime,
I’ll help you find your dad!
Mhm.
Oh...
I forgot.
You never told me what your mom does.
[Gon] It’s hard to ask about my dad,
but asking about my mom’s even harder.
It’s just that since Aunt Mito
raised me all by herself…
it feels weird, you know?
Like it’s wrong or something.
Is that how it works?
[Gon] When I was little,
Aunt Mito told me that both my parents
died in a traffic accident.
She thought if I learned my dad
was alive and a Hunter,
that I might end up just like he did, so…
She didn’t know how right she was, huh?
[Gon] When I found out about my dad…
I dunno, I guess
I kind of decided
that if he was still alive somewhere,
my mom must’ve been the one who died.
That’s pretty harsh. Seriously.
Ever since then…
I’ve thought of Aunt Mito as my mom.
The only one I’ve got.
So, there’s nothing for me to ask
and I don’t need to.
I see.
Ah, man…
I wish I had a mom
that was as cool as your Aunt Mito.
She’s awesome!
Even if she does nag a lot.
[Killua] That's nothing.
If I just say I want to go outside,
my mom immediately starts crying.
No kidding!
-She gets hysterical and everything.
-[both laughing]
[Killua] Just the other day…
-Hey, Gon…?
-Yeah?
How long will you two be staying here?
Maybe about… a month?
And after that…
I’m thinking about going
to look for my dad.
[sighs]
What’s that?
-It’s something Ging left with me.
-What?
He asked me to give this to you
when you became a Hunter.
[Gon] So Dad left this for me?
[Mito] If you want…
I’ll tell you all I know about Ging.
Well, Gon, Ging is my cousin.
My first memory of him
is actually of his back.
I ran after him everywhere he went.
I think I was about three…
Looking back on it now,
it feels like all I ever did
was try to keep up with him.
When he was just twelve years old,
Ging left the island
and took the Hunter Exam,
same as you.
Out of nowhere,
he just said he was leaving.
But when I asked him why,
all he said was…
“There’s something I want.”
But then, he never actually told me
what it was he wanted.
So, we argued.
Rather... I was the only one
doing all the arguing.
But… I never got to see Ging again
before he packed up and left.
[Great Grandmother]
Originally, you were told
your parents died
in a traffic accident, right?
That was actually
what happened to Mito’s parents.
Oh...
[Great Grandmother] It happened
not long after Ging left the island.
After that,
Ging’s dad went on a fishing trip
and then just mysteriously disappeared.
In the end,
I lost both of my sons
in a very short time.
Yes.
All that happened after he went away.
Ging eventually returned to the island
nearly ten years later.
When he did,
he was carrying you with him.
You were still just a little baby.
He just showed up,
completely out of the blue
and asked us to take care of you
for a while.
I asked him about your mother
but all he would say is
they were separated.
And right when I was about
to agree to take you,
all of a sudden, she started yelling:
“Are you crazy?!” just like that.
And I imagine everyone on the island
heard it.
Grandma! You don’t need to tell 'em that!
Now, as I was saying…
I knew we couldn’t rely on Ging
to raise you by himself.
Anyway, we really don’t know
anything about your mother.
Mito even yelled:
“Don’t you ever come back here!”
And... She was crying and everything.
Please! Grandma!
Where was I?
Oh, yes.
That’s when Ging left this little box
with us.
This girl…
She tried to throw it away so many times…
Well, I wouldn’t have had to,
if someone didn’t keep putting it back
right where it was every time!
[Great Grandmother]
If you really wanted to get rid of it,
you wouldn’t have tossed it
in a trash can.
You’d have burned it
or buried it at least.
[huffs]
[sighs] You understand?
And that’s pretty much it.
That’s every last thing
I know about Ging Freecss.
[Gon] Ging.
Ging, huh?
I mean...
Is that…?
Yeah! Yeah, that sounds better!
Ging…
Aunt Mito…
Tell me more about him.
What was Ging like when he was little?
Oh… sorry.
Does it sound weird for me
to use his name?
It just felt more… natural, I guess.
[sighs] No, that’s not it.
You want to hear what he was like
as a child?
Yes!
So… did Ging have any other friends here?
Like, his age?
Not really.
The only kids around here
were myself and your father.
Of course,
I was always practically begging him
to go and play with me,
but when I did, he would just run off.
You’d follow him
and you’d get lost every time.
Really?
Thanks!
We can always count on you, Grandma!
You’d follow Ging
way up into the mountains
but then you wouldn’t return.
The whole village would panic
when Ging came back by himself.
And it happened many times.
But when we would all go off
into the mountains to search,
Ging would always be
the first to find you,
without fail.
It didn’t matter where you were hiding.
It happened so often,
people started to wonder if it wasn’t
you and Ging’s idea of a little prank.
What? I would never do
something like that!
[Great Grandmother] Well, maybe not…
but you were always hiding in places
none of us would ever think to look!
It was almost like
you didn’t want to be found.
I don’t remember that…
Was that really how it was?
Oh! That reminds me of another time
that Ging and I…
[snoring]
[Killua] Hmm…
Okay. So...
this… is the box, huh?
Hmm... Let's see...
Uh… how do you open this thing?
I tried a whole buncha things
but it wouldn’t even budge.
Mind if I use a bit of force?
Go ahead.
All right…
[straining]
[panting]
No use.
This thing’s not normal!
I could twist open a regular steel box
no problem.
Mhmm.
And since we have no idea what’s inside,
we can’t exactly smash it, can we?
Doesn’t make a sound…
[Gon] Hmm...
[Killua] Your dad told Aunt Mito
she was only supposed to give you this
after you became a Hunter, right?
[Gon] Yeah, that’s what I heard.
Not ‘til you had become a Hunter… huh…
Whoa…
Wait a sec…
I got it!
Gon…
There’s still one thing
we haven’t tried yet!
Huh?
What’s something you have now
that you didn’t have
before you were a Hunter?
Hey! You’re right!
My Hunter License!
Except… there’s no opening for the card,
so that can’t be it.
[Killua] No, not that.
I meant Nen.
[clatter]
That’s what’s inside?
-Another box?
-Uh-huh.
Regular steel plates.
No trace of adhesives.
What is it?
[Killua] That design…
Look familiar?
[Gon] Wait this is…
I know!
This looks just like the pattern
on the promise thread
Mister Wing gave me.
The promise thread
was designed to snap
if Nen was ever used,
wasn’t it?
I’ll bet you this pattern
holds a power similar to Nen.
And it looks like…
maybe the card goes in here.
-Hey! It worked!
-Bingo!
[Gon] A ring...
and a cassette tape...
And a memory card?
Look.
That pattern’s
on the back of the ring, too.
You should be real careful
before you try putting it on.
‘Kay.
You think Ging would…
try to do something to me?
[Killua] Better safe than sorry.
Well… We can start by listening
to the cassette tape.
Guess so.
Oh! Can you copy it first?
Yeah, sure. But why?
Better safe than sorry.
[static crackling]
[Ging on a tape] Hey… Gon.
So, you became a Hunter too, huh?
Anyway…
I have a question for you.
Do you…
want to see me?
[narrator] It was the first time
Gon had ever heard his father’s voice.
And it felt to him like Ging
was reading his mind
and getting right to the point.
[theme song playing]
[Gon] Coming up:
-Gon...
-[Killua] ...and Killua’s…
[both] Hunterpedia!
-I’m Gon!
-I’m Killua!
[both] And this is our Hunterpedia!
Today, we're introducing Aunt Mito!
She raised me,
so she’ll always be my mom
as far as I’m concerned.
I really wish I had a mom like Aunt Mito.
She’s the best!
But she does nag a whole lot.
[both giggle]
[Gon] Next time: “Reply x From x Dad”!
Earthquakes, thunderstorms, fires, or Dad…
[Killua]
Which one of those scares you most?
[Gon] Aunt Mito.